-=The Last Fantasy=-
翻译：Fatreo & keaya
校对：Disenchanted
双语：Diksonhe
宇宙立方已经苏醒
The Tesseract has awakened.
它正在一个渺小世界里，人类的世界
It is on a little world, a human world.
人类想利用它的能量
They would wield its power,
他们不会成功只有我们的盟友才能利用它
but our ally knows its workings as they never will.
他将作为先锋
He is ready to lead
而我们智塔利人大军将紧随其后
and our force, our Chitauri, will follow.
给他一个地球
A world will be his.
我们拥有宇宙
The universe, yours.
至于人类，除了等死，还能做什么？
And the humans,what can they do but burn?
全体人员注意
All personnel,
疏散命令已获确认
the evacuation order has been confirmed.
（联合暗能量行动）
(DIRECTING AGENTS)
情况有多糟糕？
How bad is it?
长官，最糟的就是我们不知道情况
That's the problem, sir. We don't know.
绍韦博士四小时前侦测到立方发出的能量波
Dr. Selvig read an energy surge from the Tesseract four hours ago.
宇航局未批准绍韦进入测试阶段
NASA didn't authorise Selvig to go to test phase.
他没有测试，当时他根本不在房间里
He wasn't testing it.He wasn't even in the room.
是自动触发的
Spontaneous event.
宇宙立方自行启动？
It just turned itself on?
现在的能级达到多少了？
Where are the energy levels now?
攀升中，绍韦没能把它停下来,我们因此下令撤离
Climbing. When Selvig couldn't shut it down, we ordered evac.
完全撤离还要多久？
How long to get everyone out?
半小时应该够了
Campus should be clear in the next half-hour.
再快点
Do better.
长官，撤离也许是徒劳无益的
Sir, evacuation may be futile.
那我应该让他们都回去歇着？
We should tell them to go back to sleep?
如果我们无法控制宇宙立方的力量
If we can't control the Tesseract's energy,
也就不会有「安全距离」一说了
there may not be a minimum safe distance.
你去确保二阶段原型机的安全转移
I need you to make sure the Phase 2 prototypes are shipped out.
长官，真的要优先考虑它们？
Sir, is that really a priority right now?
除非到世界末日
Until such time as the world ends,
否则我们就得这么来
we will act as though it intends to spin on.
把下面的设备都搬走
Clear out the tech below.
二阶段原型机的每一个部件都要装车运走
Every piece of Phase 2 on a truck and gone.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
跟我来
With me.
说说情况吧，博士
Talk to me, Doctor.
局长
Director.
我们确切知道的情况有哪些？
Is there anything we know for certain?
宇宙立方不大听话
The Tesseract is misbehaving.
- 你在开玩笑？- 不，我不是开玩笑
- Is that supposed to be funny? - No, it's not funny at all.
宇宙立方不仅被唤醒了，还在自行活动
The Tesseract is not only active, she's behaving.
拔了电源试试？
I assume you pulled the plug.
它自身是个能量源
She's an energy source.
我们关闭了电源，它又重新打开
We turn off the power,she turns it back on.
如果它能级达到峰值
If she reaches peak level...
博士，这不正是我们所需要的吗？利用宇宙的能量
We prepared for this, Doctor. Harnessing energy from space.
但是我们没办法控制
But we don't have the harness.
我们离利用还差得远呢
My calculations are far from complete.
它在释放干扰与辐射
And she's throwing off interference, radiation.
低能级的伽玛射线，没什么危害
Nothing harmful,low levels of gamma radiation.
也许会有危害
That can be harmful.
巴顿探员呢？
Where's Agent Barton?
鹰眼？
The Hawk?
一如既往，在他的鹰巢里
Up in his nest, as usual.
巴顿探员，请回答
Agent Barton, report.
我让你来
I gave you this detail
是希望你能够近距离进行观察
so you could keep a close eye on things.
我站远点看得更清楚
Well, I see better from a distance.
你有看到什么东西激活它了吗？
Have you seen anything that might set this thing off?
博士，能量又达到峰值了
Doctor, it's spiking again.
没有人员进出
No one's come or gone.
绍韦也没问题
And Selvig's clean.
没人与外界联系或传输信息
No contacts, no IMs.
如果有什么扰动，也不来自这端，长官
If there was any tampering, sir,it wasn't at this end.
「来自这端」？
"At this end"?
是啊，立方不是通往宇宙另一端的通道吗？
Yeah, the Cube is a doorway to the other end of space, right?
通道是双向的
Doors open from both sides.
还是不行…
Not yet.
先生，请把矛放下
Sir, please put down the spear.
你是有心之人
You have heart.
不要
Please don't.
我还要它呢
I still need that.
没必要把事情弄那么复杂
This doesn't have to get any messier.
当然有必要
Of course it does.
我不远万里，就是为了它
I've come too far for anything else.
我是来自亚斯加特的洛基
I am Loki, of Asgard
我肩负着光荣的使命
and I am burdened with glorious purpose.
洛基
Loki,
托尔的弟弟
brother of Thor.
你我族类毫无恩怨
We have no quarrel with your people.
蚂蚁与靴子也毫无恩怨
An ant has no quarrel with a boot.
你也打算踩死我们？
Are you planning to step on us?
我给你们带来福音
I come with glad tidings
为整个世界带来解脱
of a world made free.
怎么解脱？
Free from what?
从自由中解脱
Freedom.
自由是生命中最大的谎言
Freedom is life's great lie.
当你内心接受了这观念
Once you accept that, in your heart,
你就将获得安宁
you will know peace.
你嘴上说「安宁」
Yeah, you say "peace,"
但我觉得你想表达的却恰恰相反
I kind of think you mean the other thing.
长官，霍利局长在拖延时间
Sir, Director Fury is stalling.
这地方马上就要爆炸了
This place is about to blow
我们会被压在几十米的岩石下
and drop a hundred feet of rock on us.
他想活埋了我们
He means to bury us.
像古代的法老一样
Like the pharaohs of old.
他说得对，传送门正在自我坍塌
He's right. The portal is collapsing in on itself.
离临界状态只有两分钟了
We've got maybe two minutes before this goes critical.
好吧
Well, then.
我要用这些车
I need these vehicles.
- 那是谁？ - 我也不知道
- Who's that? - They didn't tell me.
希尔！
Hill!
能听到吗？
Do you CODY?
巴顿叛变了
Barton has turned.
他们拿走了宇宙立方！拦下他们！
They have the Tesseract! Shut them down!
快走，别管它了，快走！
Okay, let's go. No, leave it. Go!
楼上撤离完毕了，长官，你得走了
We're clear upstairs, sir. You need to go.
局长？
Director?
霍利局长，能听到吗？
Director Fury, do you copy?
宇宙立方已落入敌手
The Tesseract is with a hostile force.
有人受伤，希尔，你那边呢？
I have men down. Hill?
还有很多人被埋
A lot of men still under.
不清楚有多少生还者
I don't know how many survivors.
发布命令
Sound a general call.
所有没参加救援工作的人员
I want every living soul not working rescue
都去寻找那个箱子
looking for that briefcase.
收到
Roger that.
古逊，赶回基地，这是七级事件
Coulson, get back to base. This is a Level Seven.
我们的战争
As of right now,
就此开始
we are at war.
我们该做什么？
What do we do?
复仇者联盟
今晚没按照我的预想进行
This is not how I wanted this evening to go.
我知道你对今晚的预想
I know how you wanted this evening to go.
相信我
Believe me
现实比预想好一点
this is better.
你现在为谁工作？
Who are you working for?
莱曼托夫吗？
Lermentov, yes?
他觉得
Does he think
我们需要他的允许
we have to go through him
才能运走我们的货物？
to move our cargo?
我还以为索罗霍布将军负责出口生意呢
I thought General Solohob is in charge of the export business.
索罗霍布
Solohob
只是中间人罢了
a bagman, a front.
过时的情报害了你
Your outdated information betrays you.
大名鼎鼎的黑寡妇
The famous Black Widow
也不过是个漂亮的花瓶
and she turns out to be simply another pretty face.
你真觉得我很漂亮？
You really think I'm pretty?
告诉莱曼托夫我们货物的运输
Tell Lermentov we don't need him
还轮不到他来插手
to move the tanks.
他已是明日黄花了
Tell him he is out.
不过
Well...
你也许只能用写的了
...you may have to write it down.
找她的
It's for her.
听仔细了
You listen carefully
你在114号萨伦斯基广场三楼
You're at 1-14 Silensky Plaza, 3rd floor.
有架F22在八英里外待命
We have an F-22 exactly eight miles out.
让那女人接电话，否则不等你跑到大厅
Put the woman on the phone or I will blow up the block
我就炸平整条街
before you can make the lobby.
- 我们需要你回来 - 开玩笑哪？我在工作
- We need you to come in. - Are you kidding? I'm working.
这边情况更加危急
This takes precedence.
我都审问了一半了
I'm in the middle of an interrogation.
那蠢货什么都招了
This moron is giving me everything.
我什么都没说啊
I don't give everything.
听好了，我现在走不开
Look, you can't pull me out of this right now.
娜塔莎
Natasha...
巴顿被精神控制了
Barton's been compromised.
稍等片刻
Let me put you on hold.
巴顿人呢？
Where is Barton now?
- 不知道   - 还活着吧？
- We don'tknow. - But he's alive?
应该是，等你回来再细说
We think so. I'll brief you on everything when you get back.
不过你得先和大块头聊聊
But first, we need you to talk to the big guy.
古逊你知道，相比他据我千里之外，史塔克更信任我
Coulson, you know that Stark trusts me about as far as he can throw me.
噢，我去找史塔克，你去找大块头
Oh, I've got Stark. You get the big guy.
你是谁？
Who are you?
快出去！
Get out!
会传染的！
There is sickness here!
你是医生吗？
You're a doctor.
我爸爸昏迷不醒了
My father's not waking up!
他发烧了，还一直呻吟
He has a fever and he's moaning
但眼睛却睁不开
but his eyes won't open.
慢点
Slow down.
我爸爸
My father...
像他们一样？
Like them?
求你了
Please.
你该先收钱的，班纳
You should've got paid up front, Banner.
对一个需要远离压力的人来说
You know, for a man who's supposed to be avoiding stress
你居然选择住在这种地方
you picked a hell of a place to settle.
我靠的并不是远离压力
Avoiding stress isn't the secret.
那是靠什么，瑜伽？
Then what is it? Yoga?
把我引到郊区，聪明的决定
You brought me to the edge of the city. Smart.
我猜我已被重兵包围了
I assume the whole place is surrounded.
只有你我二人
Just you and me.
你的小演员哪？
And your actress buddy?
她也是个间谍？那么小就入行了？
Is she a spy, too? They start that young?
我入行时也不大
I did.
你是谁？
Who are you?
娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫
Natasha Romanoff.
你是来取我性命的吗，罗曼诺夫小姐？
Are you here to kill me, Ms. Romanoff?
这可不是一般人能完成的任务
Because that's not going to work out for everyone.
当然不是，我是代表神盾局来的
No, of course not. I'm here on behalf of S.H.I.E.L.D.
神盾局
S.H.I.E.L.D.
他们怎么找到我的？
How did they find me?
我们一直关注着你，博士
We never lost you, Doctor.
只是保持了距离
We've kept our distance.
还帮你挡下了些不速之客
Even helped keep some other interested parties off your scent.
为什么这样？
Why?
尼克·霍利似乎很信任你
Nick Fury seems to trust you.
但现在我们需要你的加入
But now we need you to come in.
如果我拒绝呢？
What if I say no?
我会说服你的
I'll persuade you.
要是「另一个我」说不呢？
And what if the other guy says no?
你们已经一年多没出事了
You've been more than a year without an incident.
你总想让这个纪录延续吧
I don't think you want to break that streak.
好吧，我并非时时刻刻都能控制住自己
Well, I don't every time get what I want.
博士，一场全球性的大灾变很可能就要降临
Doctor, we're facing a potential global catastrophe.
这些正是我一直试图远离的
Well, those I actively try to avoid.
这东西
This
就是宇宙立方
is the Tesseract.
它有足以夷平整个地球的能量
It has the potential energy to wipe out the planet.
霍利想让我怎么做，把它吃了？
What does Fury want me to do, swallow it?
它被人夺走了，霍利希望你可以找到它
He wants you to find it. It's been taken.
它释放的伽玛射线强度太弱 我们无法追踪
It emits a gamma signature that's too weak for us to trace.
没有人比你更懂伽玛射线了
There's no one that knows gamma radiation like you do.
所以我才来找你
If there was, that's where I'd be.
那么说，霍利不是派你来抓怪物的？
So, Fury isn't after the monster?
至少他没这么说
Not that he's told me.
他什么都跟你说了？
And he tells you everything?
和霍利谈谈吧，他现在需要你
Talk to Fury. He needs you on this.
需要把我关笼子里？
He needs me in a cage?
没人打算把你关在…
No one's going to put you in a...
别骗我了！
Stop lying to me!
对不起，又失态了
I'm sorry. That was mean.
我只是想看看你的反应
I just wanted to see what you'd do.
咱们好好说话
Why don't we do this the easy way
你也别用枪指着我
where you don't use that
那家伙也就不会添乱
and the other guy doesn't make a mess.
好吗？
Okay?
娜塔莎？
Natasha?
退后
Stand down.
一切顺利
We're good here.
这叫「只有你我二人」
"Just you and me."
这有些过火了，局长
This is out of line, Director.
你试图运用你不能控制的力量
You're dealing with forces you can't control.
议员先生，你上过战场吗，真枪实弹的？
You ever been in a war, Councilman? In a firefight?
你觉得绝对控制存在吗？
Did you feel an overabundance of control?
你是说亚斯加特正与我们行星开战？
You're saying that this Asgard is declaring war on our planet?
不是亚斯加特，只是洛基
Not Asgard. Loki.
肯定不止他一人，另一个呢？
He can't be working alone.What about the other one?
他的哥哥
His brother.
根据我们的情报，他并非我们的敌人
Our intelligence says Thor is not a hostile
但他离我们太远
but he's worlds away.
我们也不能指望他帮忙
We can't depend on him to help, either.
全得看我们自己
It's up to us.
这就是你需要全力研发第二阶段的原因
Which is why you should be focusing on Phase 2.
它正是为了应对这种…
It was designed for exactly this...
二阶段尚未完成，敌人已大军压境
Phase 2 isn't ready. Our enemy is.
我们需要应急反应部队
We need a response team.
复仇者联盟计划早已停止
The Avengers Initiative was shut down.
我不是说复仇者联盟
This isn't about the Avengers.
我看过那份名单
We've seen the list.
你拥有世界上最精锐的特工组织
You're running the world's greatest covert security network
却还要把人类的命运
and you're going to leave the fate of the human race
置于那群怪胎手中
to a handful of freaks.
人类的命运不会被握在任何人手中
I'm not leaving anything to anyone.
我们确实需要应急反应部队
We need a response team.
他们也许性情孤僻，互有不合
These people may be isolated, unbalanced even
但只要引导得当，他们正是我们现在最急需的
but I believe with the right push they can be exactly what we need.
你确定？
You believe?
感情用事是赢不了战争的，局长
War isn't won by sentiment, Director.
当然，是士兵拼下来的
No, it's won by soldiers.
时间不够了
There's not enough time.
我得让它落入海里
I got to put her in the water!
你不是一个人在战斗
You won't be alone.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
这家伙竟然还活着！
This guy is still alive!
失眠了？
Trouble sleeping?
我都睡了70年了，长官,早睡够了
I slept for 70 years, sir. I think I've had my fill.
那你应该出门庆祝一下，四处看看
Then you should be out,celebrating, seeing the world.
我被冰封期间，世界正处在战乱中
When I went under, the world was at war.
等我醒来，他们说我们赢了
I wake up, they say we won.
却对我们的损失绝口不提
They didn't say what we lost.
我们一路上也犯了不少错误
We've made some mistakes along the way.
最近就有一些
Some, very recently.
你是带着任务来的吗，长官？
Are you here with a mission, sir?
是的
I am.
想把我融入外面的世界？
Trying to get me back in the world?
想让你拯救外面的世界
Trying to save it.
海德拉的秘密武器
HYDRA'S secret weapon.
这是史塔在找你的时候
Howard Stark fished that out of the ocean
从海里捞上来的
when he was looking for you.
他和我们观点相同
He thought what we think.
宇宙立方是人类开发利用永续能源的关键
The Tesseract could be the key to unlimited sustainable energy.
这正是世界所需要的
That's something the world sorely needs.
谁把它夺走了？
Who took it from you?
洛基
He's called Loki.
他远道而来
He's not from around here.
如果你加入我们，还得给你补补课
There's a lot we'll have to bring you up to speed on if you're in.
不是你不明白
The world has gotten even stranger
这世界变化快
than you already know.
我现在早见怪不怪了
At this point, I doubt anything would surprise me.
你错了，我赌10美元
Ten bucks says you're wrong.
任务报告放在你的公寓了
There's a debriefing packet waiting for you back at your apartment.
关于宇宙立方的情况
Is there anything you can tell us about the Tesseract
你有什么能告诉我们的吗？
that we ought to know now?
你们就不该把它捞出来
You should have left it in the ocean.
我这边搞定了，剩下的就看你了
Good to go on this end. The rest is up to you.
断开与输电线的连接了吗？
You disconnected the transmission lines?
我们脱离了供电网络？
Are we off the grid?
史塔大厦将成为能源自给的标志性建筑
Stark Tower is about to become a beacon of self-sustaining clean energy.
前提是弦反应堆能够替代电网正常供电
Well, assuming the arc reactor takes over and it actually works.
没问题的
I assume.
点亮吧
Light her up.
看起来如何？
How does it look?
像圣诞节一样，但更有我的特色
Like Christmas, but with more me.
我们得在普及公众意识上更进一步才行
We've got to go wider on the public awareness campaign.
你得在传媒上多造势
You need to do some press.
我明天就去华盛顿
I'm in DC tomorrow,
为接下来三座大厦选址
I'm working on the zoning for the next three buildings.
小辣椒，别扫兴，我们期待这一刻已久
Pepper, you're killing me. The moment, remember?
尽情享受现在吧
Enjoy the moment.
进来我们一块享受吧
Get in here and I will.
先生，神盾局的古逊探员来电
Sir, Agent Coulson of S.H.I.E.L.D. is on the line.
说我在外面
I'm not in.
我也的确在外面
I'm actually out.
先生，他坚持要找你
Sir, I'm afraid he's insisting.
长点骨气，佐维斯，我约会呢
Grow a spine, Jarvis. I got a date.
能级保持稳定
Levels are holding steady, I think.
那还用说，我亲自参与的
Of course they are. I was directly involved.
这让我不得不考虑一个问题
Which brings me to my next question.
当个天才感觉如何？
How does it feel to be a genius?
看来我这辈子肯定没机会考虑这个问题了
Well, I really wouldn't know, now would I?
别这样说，你可是我灵感的源泉
What do you mean? All this came from you.
不，这才是一切的源泉
No, all this came from that.
别太谦虚
Give yourself some credit. Please.
史塔大厦就像你的孩子一样
Stark Tower is your baby.
你有12%的功劳
Give yourself 12% of the credit.
12%？
12%?
15%，不能再多了
An argument can be made for 15.
就12%还叫「我的孩子」？
12%? My baby?
毕竟所有的重活都是我干的
Well, I did do all the heavy lifting.
准确地说，重物都是我搬的
Literally, I lifted the heavy things.
对了，说说混乱的安保系统
And, sorry, but the security snafu?
都怪你
- That was on you. - Oh.
- 我的私人电梯 - 你是说我们的电梯？
- My private elevator... - You mean our elevator?
挤满了浑身臭汗的工人
...It was teeming with sweaty workmen.
我会为刚才分功的评论付出代价的，对吧？
I'm going to pay for that comment about percentages in some subtle way later, aren't I?
可没那么简单
It's not going to be that subtle.
这么说吧
I'll tell you what.
下一座大厦上将挂上「宝芝」的大名
The next building is gonna say "Potts" on the tower.
还是写租约上吧
On the lease.
打电话问你妈你能不能留下过夜
Call your mom. Can you bunk over?
先生，您的电话
Sir, the telephone.
我的规程被改写了
I'm afraid my protocols are being overridden.
史塔先生，我有事找你
Mr. Stark, we need to talk.
你正在与东尼·史塔的仿生假体通话
You have reached the life model decoy of Tony Stark.
- 请留言 - 我有急事
- Please leave a message. - This is urgent.
那就快点说
Then leave it urgently.
安保漏洞，你的错
Security breach. It's on you.
- 史塔先生 - 费尔，快请进
- Mr. Stark. - Phil! Come in.
「费尔」？
"Phil"?
我不能久留
I can't stay.
他名叫「探员」
His first name is "Agent."
快请进，我们正在庆祝
Come on in. We're celebrating.
正因此他不能久留
Which is why he can't stay.
请尽快阅读这些资料
We need you to look this over as soon as possible.
我不喜欢别人递给我东西
I don't like being handed things.
没事，我喜欢别人递给我东西
That's fine, because I love to be handed things.
我们换一换
So, let's trade.
谢谢你
Thank you.
正式咨询时间是每隔一周的 周四的早8点到下午5点
Official consulting hours are between 8 and 5 every other Thursday.
我不是来咨询的
This isn't a consultation.
是关于复仇者联盟？
Is this about the Avengers?
我对此一无所知
Which I know nothing about.
我记得复仇者联盟计划早已废弃
The Avengers Initiative was scrapped, I thought.
我连入选资格都没有
And I didn't even qualify.
我也不大清楚
I didn't know that either.
何况我反复无常，偏执自恋
Apparently I'm volatile, self-obsessed,
和他人难以相处
don't play well with others.
这个我深有感触
That I did know.
现在没空管性格了
This isn't about personality profiles anymore.
无所谓了，宝芝小姐，可以过来下吗？
Whatever. Ms. Potts, got a second?
稍等
Half a mo.
我还以为我们能共度良宵哪
You know, I thought we were having a moment.
我正在享受那12%的良宵
I was having 12% of a moment.
事态看来挺严重的，费尔惊魂未定
This seems serious. Phil's pretty shaken.
你知道那是…你怎么叫他费尔？
How would you know if it's... Why is he "Phil"?
这都是些什么？
What is all this?
这些是
This is
看吧
this.
我今晚就飞华盛顿
I'm going to take the jet to DC tonight.
明天吧
Tomorrow.
你资料要看，还不少呢
You have homework. You have a lot of homework.
要是我不看呢？
Well, what if I didn't?
- 你不看？- 是啊
- If you didn't? - Yeah.
你是说你已经看完了？
You mean when you've finished?
那好吧
Well, then...
就这么定了，一路顺风
Square deal. Fly safe.
好好干
Work hard.
去拉瓜迪亚机场顺路吗？
So, any chance you're driving by LaGuardia?
- 我载你去吧 - 太棒了
- I can drop you. - Fantastic.
说说那个大提琴手吧
I want to hear
你们还有戏吗？
about the cellist. Is that still a thing?
她搬回波特兰了
She moved back to Portland.
真的吗？
What? BOO!
我们距基地还有40分钟航程，长官
We're about 40 minutes out from home base, sir.
班纳博士想复制我曾注射的血清吗？
So, this Dr. Banner was trying to replicate the serum they used on me?
很多人都想
A lot of people were.
你是世界上第一个超级英雄
You were the world's first superhero.
班纳认为破解艾斯金的原始配方的关键
Banner thought gamma radiation might hold the key to unlocking
就在于伽玛射线
Erskine's original formula.
只可惜事与愿违，不是吗？
Didn't really go his way, did it?
差不多吧
Not so much.
不过他不变身的时候就像史蒂芬·霍金一样
When he's not that thing, though, the guy's like a Stephen Hawking.
我是指智力方面
He's like a smart person.
说实话
I gotta say,
十分荣幸能与你正式会面
it's an honour to meet you officially.
我是，我以前也算见过你
I've sort of met you. I mean,
是你还在沉睡的时候
I watched you while you were sleeping.
你被发现冰封不醒时
I mean, I was present
我就在场
while you were unconscious from the ice.
你能加入我们
You know, it's really just a huge honour
实在是太荣幸了
to have you on board this...
希望我可以胜任吧
I hope I'm the man for the job.
你当然可以，绝对的
Oh, you are. Absolutely.
我们对你的战斗服做了些改动
We made some modifications to the uniform.
还采纳了些我的意见
I had a little design input.
战斗服？
The uniform?
那些星条旗图案…
Aren't the stars and stripes a little
是不是有些过时？
old-fashioned?
鉴于目前局势
With everything that's happening
和未来可能发生的事情
and the things that are about to come to light,
人们可能需要一些过去的美国精神
people might just need a little old-fashioned.
智塔利人已经等不及了
The Chitauri grow restless.
让他们做好战备吧
Let them gird themselves.
我将引领他们打一场光荣的战役
I will lead them in the glorious battle.
战役？
Battle?
对付那些弱小的地球人？
Against the meagre might of Earth?
一场光荣的闪电战
Glorious, not lengthy.
只要你的大军如你所言般强大
If your force is as formidable as you claim.
你竟然质疑我们？
You question us?
你质疑的人
You question him,
正是在你战败且遭受流放时
he who put the sceptre in your hand?
授予你权杖
Who gave you ancient knowledge and new purpose
并给予你远古知识与新的目标的人
when you were cast out, defeated?
我是国王
I was a king!
亚斯加特的法定国王
The rightful king of Asgard,
可惜遭人背叛
betrayed.
你鼠目寸光
Your ambition is little
满是幼稚之想
and born of childish need.
我们放眼地球之外
We look beyond the Earth
那些即将被宇宙立方开启的无垠星空
to the greater worlds the Tesseract will unveil.
可惜宇宙立方还在我手上
You don't have the Tesseract yet.
我可没有威胁你
I don't threaten.
但只要传送门没有打开
But until I open the doors,
你的大军没有归于我的麾下
until your force is mine to command,
你的一切都只是空谈
you are but words.
你会得到想要的战争的，亚斯加特人
You will have your war, Asgardian.
如果你失败了
If you fail,
宇宙立方落入他人之手
if the Tesseract is kept from us,
那将没有任何国家，任何星球
there will be no realm, no barren moon,
哪怕一道裂隙供你躲藏
no crevice where he cannot find you.
你知道苦痛的滋味吗？
You think you know pain?
他会让你体验真正的痛不欲生
He will make you long for something sweet as pain.
把美国队长的装备卸载下来
Stow the captain's gear.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
罗曼诺夫探员，这位是罗杰斯队长
Agent Romanoff, Captain Rogers.
- 你好，女士 - 你好
- Ma'am. - Hi.
他们在舰桥等着你
They need you on the bridge.
他们开始面部识别追踪了
They're starting the face-trace.
回见
See you there.
你在冰中被发现可轰动一时呢
It was quite the buzz around here, finding you in the ice.
我以为古逊会乐晕了呢
I thought Coulson was gonna swoon.
他没让你在美国队长集换卡上签名？
Did he ask you to sign his Captain America trading cards yet?
集换卡？
Trading cards?
珍藏版的，他可引以为傲呢
They're vintage. He's very proud.
班纳博士
Dr. Banner.
你好啊
Yeah, hi.
我听说你会过来
They told me you would be coming.
他们说你能找到那立方
Word is, you can find the Cube.
就说了这些？
Is that the only word on me?
我就关心这些
Only word I care about.
这些一定让你倍感陌生吧
It must be strange for you, all of this.
其实，我倒觉得似曾相识
Well, this is actually kind of familiar.
先生们，你们最好赶紧进去
Gentlemen, you might want to step inside in a minute.
这儿马上就难以呼吸了
It's going to get a little hard to breathe.
空勤人员，请清空甲板
Flight crew, secure the deck.
这是潜艇吗？
Is this a submarine?
真的？
Really?
想把我关在水下加压的金属管子里？
They want me in a submerged, pressurised, metal container?
不，好像更糟
No, no, this is much worse.
悬停能量检查完毕，供给稳定
Hover power check complete. Position cyclic.
动力增至8%
Increase collective to 8.0%.
准备全速启航
Preparing for maximum performance takeoff.
输出功率调至最高
Increase output to capacity.
动力性能已达上限
Power plant performing at capacity.
准备完毕
We are clear.
全部引擎运转正常
All engines operating.
神盾局193.6号应急规程已启动
S.H.I.E.L.D. Emergency Protocol 193.6 in effect.
- 已到达预定高度，长官 - 很好
- We are at level, sir. - Good.
我们消失吧
Let's vanish.
开启光线反射板
Engage retro-reflection panels.
光线反射板开启完毕
Reflection panels engaged.
先生们
Gentlemen.
感谢你的到来，博士
Doctor, thank you for coming.
多谢你的善意邀请
Thanks for asking nicely.
那我要在这呆多久？
So, how long am I staying?
等我们拿到宇宙立方
Once we get our hands on the Tesseract,
你就可以走了
you're in the wind.
你那边有何进展？
Where are you with that?
我们在扫描地球上每一个
We're sweeping every wirelessly accessible
连接到无线网络的摄像头
camera on the planet.
手机，笔记本电脑…
Cell phones, laptops...
只要它连上了卫星，就成了我们的眼线
If it's connected to a satellite, it's eyes and ears for us.
这样还是无法及时找到他们
That's still not gonna find them in time.
你得缩小搜寻范围
You have to narrow your field.
你们有多少光谱仪可用？
How many spectrometers do you have access to?
- 你要多少？ - 通知所有可以联系上的实验室
- How many are there? - Call every lab you know.
让他们把光谱仪放在房顶
Tell them to put the spectrometers on the roof
调整成接收伽玛射线的状态
and calibrate them for gamma rays.
我会草拟一个聚类识别的追踪算法
I'll rough out a tracking algorithm, basic cluster recognition.
最少能排除一些区域
At least we could rule out a few places.
能给我找个干活的地方吗？
Do you have somewhere for me to work?
罗曼诺夫探员
Agent Romanoff,
能把班纳博士带到他的实验室去吗？
could you show Dr. Banner to his laboratory, please?
你会喜欢的，博士，那儿应有尽有
You're gonna love it, Doc. We got all the toys.
放那边去
Put it over there.
你从哪找的这些人？
Where did you find all these people?
神盾局树敌无数，博士
S.H.I.E.L.D. has no shortage of enemies, Doctor.
这是你需要的材料吗？
Is this the stuff you need?
是啊，铱
Yeah, iridium.
陨石里找的，它可以产生反质子
It's found in meteorites. It forms anti-protons.
这东西很难搞到
It's very hard to get hold of.
如果神盾局知道你需要它，就更难了
Especially if S.H.I.E.L.D. knows you need it.
这我就不知道了
Well, I didn't know.
Hey!
宇宙立方向我展现了太多
The Tesseract has shown me so much.
不止是知识，更是真理
It's more than knowledge. It's truth.
我知道
I know.
你看到了什么，巴顿探员？
What did it show you, Agent Barton?
我的下一个目标
My next target.
告诉我你需要些什么
Tell me what you need.
引开他们的注意力
I need a distraction.
和能通过视网膜扫描的眼球
And an eyeball.
如果…不是太麻烦的话
I mean, if it's not too much trouble.
没事，不麻烦
No, no. It's fine.
那是套珍藏版
It's a vintage set.
花了我好几年才收集齐
It took me a couple of years to collect them all.
全新的
Near mint.
边角有些泛黄，不过…
Slight foxing around the edges, but...
发现疑似目标，吻合度67%
We got a hit. A 67% match.
等等，交叉匹配，吻合度79%
Wait. Cross match, 79%.
位置在哪？
Location?
德国斯图加特国王大街28号
Stuttgart, Germany. 28 Königstrasse.
他就没打算躲起来
He's not exactly hiding.
队长
Captain,
看你的了
you're up.
（视网膜扫瞄… 通过认证 解锁）
给我跪下
Kneel before me.
我说了
I said
跪下！
kneel!
早这样不就好了？
Is not this simpler?
这不正是你们的本性？
Is this not your natural state?
这是关于人性无人道破的真理
It's the unspoken truth of humanity,
渴望被奴役
that you crave subjugation.
自由那看似光鲜的诱惑吞噬了生活的乐趣
The bright lure of freedom diminishes your life's joy
热衷于追求权力
in a mad scramble for power,
沉溺于渴望认同
for identity.
你们生来就该被奴役
You were made to be ruled.
到头来
In the end,
你们还是会臣服
you will always kneel.
不会向你这种人臣服的
Not to men like you.
你再也找不出第二个我了
There are no men like me.
你这种人多了
There are always men like you.
看看这老家伙
Look to your elder, people.
就让他做你们的反面教材吧
Let him be an example.
你看，上次我来德国
You know, the last time I was in Germany,
就有一个人凌驾于众人之上
and saw a man standing above everybody else,
我们就不欢而散
we ended up disagreeing.
美国大兵
The soldier.
过时的家伙
The man out of time.
至少我不是快要死的那个
I'm not the one who's out of time.
洛基，放下武器，立即投降
Loki, drop the weapon and stand down.
跪下
Kneel.
不可能
- Not today!
他的分身到处都是
The guy's all over the place.
罗曼诺夫探员，想我了没？
Agent Romanoff. You miss me?
（系统被改写）
出招吧，小驯鹿
Make your move, Reindeer Games.
这才乖
Good move.
史塔先生
Mr. Stark.
队长
Captain.
他说什么了吗？
Is he saying anything?
什么都不说
Not a word.
把他带回来，我们时间不多了
Just get him here. We're low on time.
有些不对劲
I don't like it.
怎么，因为邪神大人如此轻易的投降？
What, Rock of Ages giving up so easily?
我觉得没那么简单
I don't remember it being that easy.
这家伙挺厉害的
This guy packs a wallop.
不过你那么大年纪功夫也挺不错的
Still, you are pretty spry for an older fellow.
保持健康的秘诀是什么，做普拉提？
What's your thing, Pilates?
什么？
What?
和健美操差不多
It's like calisthenics.
你在当冰棍队长的时候
You might have missed a couple of things
错过了很多事情
doing time as a Capsicle.
霍利没说他也叫你了
Fury didn't tell me he was calling you in.
是啊，霍利没说的事多了
Yeah, there's a lot of things Fury doesn't tell you.
怎么打雷了？
Where's this coming from?
怎么了？你还怕打雷？
What's the matter? Are you scared of a little lightning?
我只是不喜欢随之而来的家伙
I'm not overly fond of what follows.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
半路杀出了这家伙
And now there's that guy.
又一个亚斯加特人？
Another Asgardian?
- 他是自己人吗？ - 这无关紧要
- That guy's a friendly? - Doesn't matter.
无论他杀了洛基或是放了他宇宙立方就找不到了
If he frees Loki or kills him, the Tesseract's lost.
史塔，我们需要攻击计划
Stark, we need a plan of attack!
我有个计划，攻击
I have a plan. Attack.
要是我可不管这闲事，队长
I'd sit this one out, Cap.
我可做不到
I don't see how I can.
他们都是从神域而来基本上就是神
These guys come from legend. They're basically gods.
世上只有上帝一个神，女士
There's only one God, ma'am.
而且他才不会打扮成那样
And I'm pretty sure he doesn't dress like that.
宇宙立方在哪？
Where is the Tesseract?
我也很想念你
I missed you, too.
我像是跟你开玩笑的吗？
Do I look to be in a gaming mood?
你应该感谢我
You should thank me.
彩虹桥已毁，奥丁汇聚了多少暗能
With the Bifrost gone, how much dark energy
才把你传送到
did the Allfather have to muster to conjure you here
你心爱的地球上？
to your precious Earth?
我还以为你死了
I thought you dead.
你为我哀悼了？
Did you mourn?
我们都哀悼了，我们的父王…
We all did. Our father...
你的父王
Your father.
他把我的身世告诉你了，不是吗？
He did tell you my true parentage, did he not?
我们从小一块长大
We were raised together.
一起嬉戏，一同打闹
We played together, we fought together.
你都不记得了吗？
Do you remember none of that?
我只记得阴影
I remember a shadow.
我活在你伟大所投射的阴影中
Living in the shade of your greatness.
我无法忘记你把我扔下深渊
I remember you tossing me into an abyss.
王位是我的，也应该由我来继承
I, who was, and should be, king!
所以你践踏我心爱的世界
So you take the world I love as a recompense
以补偿你所遭受的怠慢？
for your imagined slights?
不，地球在我的庇护之下，洛基
No. The Earth is under my protection, Loki.
你保护得可真好啊
And you're doing a marvellous job with that.
人们成群结队地彼此厮杀
The humans slaughter each other in droves
你却在一旁干着急
while you idly fret.
我要统治他们，难道有错吗？
I mean to rule them, as why should I not?
你自认高他们一等？
You think yourself above them?
那当然
Well, yes.
那你就没懂得统治的真谛，弟弟
Then you miss the truth of ruling, brother.
王位并不适合你
A throne would suit you ill.
我见过许多你未知的世界
I've seen worlds you've never known about!
奥丁逊，在流放途中，我已成长
I have grown, Odinson, in my exile.
我见识了宇宙立方的真正力量
I have seen the true power of the Tesseract,
等我拥有了它…
and when I wield it...
谁向你展示了它的力量？
Who showed you this power?
是谁在背后操纵着你这个国王迷？
Who controls the would-be king?
- 我就是国王！- 别妄想了！
- I am a king! - Not here!
交出宇宙立方！
You give up the Tesseract!
放下痴心妄想！
You give up this poisonous dream!
跟我回家
You come home.
不在我手上
I don't have it.
你需要立方来带我回去
You need the Cube to bring me home.
但我把它转移了，我也不知道在哪
But I've sent it off, I know not where.
听好了，弟弟
You listen well, brother.
我听着哪
I'm listening.
不许再碰我了
Do not touch me again.
那你也别拿我东西
Then don't take my stuff.
我看你是不知道厉害
You have no idea what you're dealing with.
这是中央公园的莎翁戏剧节吗？
Shakespeare in the Park?
取帘为氅，令堂知否？
Doth Mother know you wear-eth her drapes?
这不关你的事，铁皮人
This is beyond you, metal man.
洛基将面临亚斯加特律法的审判
Loki will face Asgardian justice.
让他把立方交出来，他就归你了在此之前
He gives up the Cube, he's all yours. Until then,
最好别碍事
stay out of the way.
你个外域来客
- Tourist.
好吧
Okay.
能量达到400%
Power at 400% capacity.
尝尝这个
How about that?
Hey!
够了没
That's enough.
我不知道你来此有何目的
Now, I don't know what you plan on doing here.
我来这里终结洛基的阴谋
I've come here to put an end to Loki's schemes.
用行动说话，把锤子放下
Then prove it. Put that hammer down.
啊…不行
Yeah... No.
这可不是个好主意，他爱死他的锤子了
Bad call. He loves his hammer.
想让我放下锤子？
You want me to put the hammer down?
打够了没？
Are we done, here?
先跟你说清楚了
In case it's unclear,
如果你想逃跑
if you try to escape,
哪怕轻轻挠那玻璃一下
if you so much as scratch that glass,
你就会随着这监牢从万米高空坠落
it's 30,000 feet straight down in a steel trap.
懂了吗？
You get how that works?
你是蚂蚁，我是靴子
Ant, boot.
这笼子可真不错
It's an impressive cage.
不过，不是为我建造的吧
Not built, I think, for me.
它是为个比你强大得多的东西建的
Built for something a lot stronger than you.
我有所耳闻
Oh, I've heard.
一头愚蠢的野兽
A mindless beast.
还假装自己是普通人
Makes play he's still a man.
你该有多绝望
How desperate are you,
才会找来这种怪胎作援兵？
that you call on such lost creatures to defend you?
我有多绝望？
How desperate am I?
你以战争威胁我们的世界
You threaten my world with war.
你窃取自己无法掌控的能量
You steal a force you can't hope to control.
你嘴边挂着安宁，却以挥舞手中屠刀为乐
You talk about peace, and you kill because it's fun.
你逼我孤注一掷
You have made me very desperate.
你会为你的所作所为后悔的
You might not be glad that you did.
噢
Ooh.
功亏一篑让你无比痛苦吧
It burns you to have come so close.
获取宇宙立方，拥有其中能量
To have the Tesseract, to have power,
无尽的能量
unlimited power.
用来干什么？
And for what?
点起照亮人类前路的明灯
A warm light for all mankind to share.
然后认识到真正力量的本来面目
And then to be reminded what real power is.
如果真正力量想要看杂志解闷，记得跟我说
Well, let me know if "real power" wants a magazine or something.
你都看他看入迷了吧
He really grows on you, doesn't he?
洛基是在拖延时间
Loki's gonna drag this out.
托尔，他到底想干什么？
So, Thor, what's his play?
他拥有一支智塔利大军
He has an army called the Chitauri.
他们并非来自亚斯加特或任何已知的世界
They're not of Asgard, nor any world known.
洛基想带领他们攻打地球
He means to lead them against your people.
他们将助洛基夺取地球
They will win him the Earth,
而我想洛基会将宇宙立方交给他们
in return, I suspect, for the Tesseract.
来自外太空的
An army
大军
from outer space.
那么他正在建立另一个传送门
So, he's building another portal.
这就是他带走艾力·绍韦的原因
That's what he needs Erik Selvig for.
绍韦？
Selvig?
- 他是位天体物理学家 - 我的朋友
- He's an astrophysicist. - He's a friend.
洛基用某种魔法控制了他
Loki has him under some kind of spell,
还有我们的一位探员
along with one of ours.
洛基为何如此轻易的束手就擒
I want to know why Loki let us take him.
他在这无法领导任何大军
He's not leading an army from here.
我觉得不应该把注意力集中在洛基身上
I don't think we should be focusing on Loki.
他的想法难以捉摸
That guy's brain is a bag full of cats.
可以说就是个疯子
You could smell crazy on him.
说话注意点
Have care how you speak.
尽管洛基蛮不讲理，但他还是亚斯加特人
Loki is beyond reason, but he is of Asgard.
也是我的弟弟
And he is my brother.
他在两天内杀了80个人
He killed 80 people in two days.
不是亲弟弟
He's adopted.
让我们往机械上想想吧
I think it's about the mechanics.
铱，他们要铱干什么？
Iridium... What do they need the iridium for?
铱是一种稳定剂
It's a stabilising agent.
我是说，随便那个周末
I'm just saying, pick a weekend.
我开飞机载你去波特兰
I'll fly you to Portland.
多培养一下情感
Keep love alive.
这样传送门就不会像神盾局的那个一样自我坍塌了
It means the portal won't collapse on itself like it did at S.H.I.E.L.D.
不打不相识，你那一下真狠
No hard feelings, Point Break. You've got a mean swing.
同时铱还可以让洛基根据需要
Also, it means the portal can open as wide
把传送门开得更大，持续时间更长
and stay open as long, as Loki wants.
升起后桅，全速启航
Raise the mizzenmast. Jib the topsails.
那人在玩「小蜜蜂」
That man is playing Galaga.
他自以为别人看不到，但被我发现了
He thought we wouldn't notice, but we did.
霍利的视线如何兼顾两侧？
How does Fury even see these?
他会转身
He turns.
那多累啊
Sounds exhausting.
剩余的原材料
The rest of the raw materials,
巴顿探员都能轻松得到
Agent Barton can get his hands on pretty easily.
现在他只需要一个部件
The only major component he still needs
高能量密度的动力源
is a power source of high-energy density.
来启动立方
Something to kick-start the Cube.
你什么时候变成热核天体物理学家了？
When did you become an expert in thermonuclear astrophysics?
昨天晚上
Last night.
看看任务资料，绍韦的笔记和精选的理论论文
The packet, Selvig's notes, the extraction theory papers.
难道只有我看了？
Am I the only one who did the reading?
洛基需要某种特定的能源吗？
Does Loki need any particular kind of power source?
他得把立方加热到1.2亿开氏度
He would have to heat the Cube to 120-million Kelvin
以突破库仑势垒
just to break through the Coulomb barrier.
除非绍韦找到
Unless Selvig has figured out how to stabilise
稳定量子隧道效应的办法
the quantum tunneling effect.
如果他真找到了
Well, if he could do that,
就可以用地球上任一个反应堆完成重离子聚变
he could achieve heavy ion fusion at any reactor on the planet.
终于有会说人话的了
Finally, someone who speaks English.
是那么回事吗？
Is that what just happened?
很高兴见到你，班纳博士
It's good to meet you, Dr. Banner.
你在反电子冲撞领域中的成就无人能及
Your work on antielectron collisions is unparalleled.
我也是你失控时变成的
And I'm a huge fan of the way you lose control
那个绿色大怪兽的铁杆粉丝
and turn into an enormous green rage-monster.
谢谢
Thanks.
班纳博士只为追寻立方而来
Dr. Banner is only here to track the Cube.
我希望你可以助他一臂之力
I was hoping you might join him.
从他的权杖开始看吧
I would start with that stick of his.
它也许有魔力
It may be magical,
但用法和海德拉的武器挺像的
but it works an awful lot like a HYDRA weapon.
我不大清楚，但它由立方所驱动
I don't know about that, but it is powered by the Cube.
我想知道洛基怎么用它
And I would like to know how Loki used it
把我见过的最机警的两个人
to turn two of the sharpest men I know
变成他的跟班飞猴
into his personal flying monkeys.
猴子？你在说什么
Monkeys? I do not understand.
绿野仙踪，我知道
I do.
我知道这典故
I understood that reference.
我们开始吧，博士？
Shall we play, Doctor?
这边请，先生
This way, sir.
伽玛读数和绍韦报告上
The gamma readings are definitely consistent
宇宙立方的读数完全一致
with Selvig's reports of the Tesseract.
但处理起来要花好几周时间
But it's going to take weeks to process.
如果可以绕过他们的主机
If we bypass their mainframe
连接到主群集
and direct route to the Homer cluster,
我们可以做到每秒600兆次浮点运算
we can clock this at around 600 teraflops.
可惜我只带了牙刷
All I packed was a toothbrush.
有空来史塔大厦玩玩
You know, you should come by Stark Tower sometime.
顶10层用作科研
Top ten floors, all R&D.
包你喜欢
You'd love it. It's Candy Land.
谢了，上次我在纽约
Thanks, but the last time I was in New York,
差点炸了哈莱姆区
I kind of broke Harlem.
我保证这次你会毫无压力
Well, I promise a stress-free environment.
毫不紧张，绝无意外
No tension, no surprises.
- Ow!
Hey! - Nothing?
你疯了？
Are you nuts?
天晓得
Jury's out.
自制力不错啊
You really have got a lid on it, haven't you?
有何秘诀？
What's your secret?
玩爵士乐还是磕药？
Mellow jazz, bongo drums huge bag of weed?
你很爱开玩笑吗？
Is everything a joke to you?
好玩嘛
Funny things are.
这会令大家身陷险境
Threatening the safety of everyone on this ship
何来好玩
isn't funny.
对不起，博士
No offence, Doc.
没关系，若我连这小刺激都适应不了
It's all right, I wouldn't have come aboard
就不会登船了
if I couldn't handle pointy things.
大块头，你太谨慎了，放松点
You're tip-toeing, big man. You need to strut.
而你需要专注解决问题，史塔先生
And you need to focus on the problem, Mr. Stark.
难道我没有做事吗？
Do you think I'm not?
为何霍利现在才召集我们？
Why did Fury call us in? Why now? Why not before?
有何内幕？
What isn't he telling us?
消除所有疑惑，我才能做事
I can't do the equation unless I have all the variables.
你指霍利有所隐瞒？
You think Fury's hiding something?
毕竟他可是特务中的佼佼者
He's a spy. Captain, he's "the" spy.
深不可测
His secrets have secrets.
他也有同感吧？
It's bugging him, too. Isn't it?
Uh...
我只想完成我在这里的工作
I just want to finish my work here, and...
博士?
Doctor?
点起照亮人类前程的明灯
"A warm light for all mankind."
提及宇宙立方时，洛基这样对霍利说道
Loki's jab at Fury about the Cube.
我听见了
I heard it.
是说给你听的
I think that was meant for you.
即使巴顿没跟洛基提过史塔大厦
Even if Barton didn't tell Loki about the tower,
他也可以由新闻得知
it was still all over the news.
史塔大厦？高耸又奇丑…
The Stark Tower? That big, ugly
的纽约建筑大厦？
building in New York?
由弦反应炉供能，能源可自生
It's powered by an arc reactor, a self-sustaining energy source.
大厦能自给自足一年吗？
That building will run itself for, what, a year?
只是个试点
It's just the prototype.
我可是目前洁净能源的先驱者
I'm kind of the only name in clean energy right now.
这就是他的目的
That's what he's getting at.
为何神盾局没招揽他加入宇宙立方计划？
So, why didn't S.H.I.E.L.D. bring him in on the Tesseract project?
当初为何他们会涉足能源产业？
What are they doing in the energy business in the first place?
一旦我获悉所有神盾局的机密
I should probably look into that once my decryption program
我会着手调查此事
finishes breaking into all of S.H.I.E.L.D.'s secure files.
对不起，你说…
I'm sorry. Did you say...
自我上船来，佐维斯就一直运行破解程式
Jarvis has been running it since I hit the bridge.
几小时后，我就可以得知
In a few hours, I'll know every dirty secret
神盾局的隐藏机密
S.H.I.E.L.D. has ever tried to hide.
吃蓝莓吗?
Blueberry?
你仍为没被招揽而百思不解？
Yet you're confused about why they didn't want you around.
情报机构竟然害怕聪明人？
An intelligence organisation that fears intelligence?
真没劲
Historically, not awesome.
洛基想挑拨离间
I think Loki's trying to wind us up.
洛基肯定意图发动战争
This is a man who means to start a war
继续这样下去，岂不正中他下怀
and if we don't stay focused, he'll succeed.
既然有命在身，就要服从
We have orders. We should follow them.
我可不喜欢臣服于他人
Following's not really my style.
你想出风头吧？
And you're all about style, aren't you?
在座各位
Of the people in this room,
当中有人着装奇异
which one is, A, wearing a spangly outfit,
简直不成气候
and, B, not of use?
斯蒂夫，你不觉得不自在吗？
Steve, tell me none of this smells a little funky to you.
找立方吧
Just find the Cube.
他就是让我父亲赞不绝口的家伙？
That's the guy my dad never shut up about?
他们应该再次冷藏他
I'm wondering if they shouldn't have kept him on ice.
Huh.
他很了解洛基
The guy's not wrong about Loki.
他看事情比我们敏锐
He does have the jump on us.
他就像导火索
What he's got is an Acme dynamite kit.
迟早会搞砸一切
It's going to blow up in his face.
到时我拭目以待
And I'm going to be there when it does.
我就会由新闻得知过程
Yeah. I'll read all about it.
不如你也着装加入我们
Uh-huh. Or you'll be suiting up with the rest of us.
你看，可我没有护甲
You see, I don't get a suit of armour.
赤手空拳打战简直寻死
I'm exposed. Like a nerve.
太糟糕了
It's a nightmare.
每时每刻都有一堆炮弹碎片
I've got a cluster of shrapnel trying every second
试图侵入我心脏
to crawl its way into my heart.
这个保护了我
This stops it.
这个小光环是我身体一部分了
This little circle of light, it's part of me now,
不止是护甲
not just armour.
是可怕的天赐
It's a terrible privilege.
- 不过你可以控制它 - 我只是学会使用
- But you can control it. - Because I learned how.
不能这样说
It's different.
我听闻过你的事情
Hey, I read all about your accident.
如此强的伽马射线早该杀死你
That much gamma exposure should have killed you.
你意指绿巨人浩克
So you're saying that the Hulk...
他救了我？
The other guy saved my life?
说得好
That's nice.
观点不错，可为什么救我？
It's a nice sentiment. Saved it for what?
我们会知道的
I guess we'll find out.
届时你就会闷闷不乐
You may not enjoy that.
说不定你会高兴起来
And you just might.
（机密仓库10-C）
洛基一带走博士
As soon as Loki took the doctor,
我们就把珍儿转移了
we moved Jane Foster.
挪威有个一流的天文台
They've got an excellent observatory in Tromsø.
珍儿昨天应邀过去做顾问
She was asked to consult there very suddenly yesterday.
酬劳不菲，有私人飞机，离这里很远
Handsome fee, private plane, very remote.
她会很安全
She'll be safe.
多谢
Thank you.
洛基带走艾力博士，并非巧合
It's no accident, Loki taking Erik Selvig.
不知道事后洛基会如何处置博士
I dread what he plans for him once he's done.
艾力是个好人
Erik is a good man.
他经常提及你
He talks about you a lot.
你改变了他一生
You changed his life.
你也改变了这里一切
You changed everything around here.
还是原来的好
They were better as they were.
在永恒国度，我们自命不凡
We pretend on Asgard that we're more advanced
来到凡间却如巨兽
but we come here, battling like bilge snipe.
- 什么？ - 巨兽
- Like what? - Bilge snipe.
巨型，有鳞，有鹿角
You know, huge, scaly, big antlers.
- 这里没有吧？ - 应该没有
- You don't have those? - I don't think so.
它们很讨厌
Well, they are repulsive.
它们践踏所经之处
And they trample everything in their path.
我首次来地球时，亦使洛基迁怒于此
When I first came to Earth, Loki's rage followed me here,
人类损失惨重
and your people paid the price.
如今历史再现
And now, again.
年壮时我热衷战斗
In my youth, I courted war.
战争还没有开始
War hasn't started yet.
你认为你可以令洛基告诉我们
You think you could make Loki tell us
立方在哪吗？
where the Tesseract is?
洛基深不可测
I do not know. Loki's mind is far afield.
他不但要权力，还要报复我
It's not just power he craves, it's vengeance, upon me.
为求达到目的，他会不择手段
There's no pain would prise his need from him.
简直不知天高地厚
A lot of guys think that until the pain starts.
你有何吩咐
What are you asking me to do?
那你有何计划？
I'm asking, what are you prepared to do?
洛基已是阶下囚
Loki is a prisoner.
为何我觉得他才是唯一想留在船上的人？
Then why do I feel like he's the only person on this boat that wants to be here?
可以潜近我身边的人不多
There's not many people who can sneak up on me.
你猜到是我了
But you figured I'd come.
不过
After.
应该是在局长折磨我后
After whatever tortures Fury can concoct,
你会如知己般出现，安慰我
you would appear as a friend, as a balm.
接着我就会同你合作
And I would cooperate.
你对巴顿特工做过什么？
I want to know what you've done to Agent Barton.
我只是打开他心境
I would say I've expanded his mind.
那你赢得一切后
And once you've won,
成为众神之王以后
once you're king of the mountain,
会如何处置他？
what happens to his mind?
爱之心切吗？
Is this love, Agent Romanoff?
爱是孩童玩意，我只是欠他人情
Love is for children. I owe him a debt.
告诉我
Tell me.
效力神盾局前
Before I worked for S.H.I.E.L.D... I, uh...
我已稍有名气
Well, I made a name for myself.
因为天赋异禀
I have a very specific skill set.
所以肆无忌惮
I didn't care who I used it for, or on.
因此上了神盾局的黑名单
I got on S.H.I.E.L.D.'s radar in a bad way.
巴顿特工奉命刺杀我
Agent Barton was sent to kill me.
但他没杀我
He made a different call.
若我答应放过他，你会如何报答？
And what will you do if I vow to spare him?
我不会放你出来的
Not let you out.
相当有趣
No, but I like this.
自身难保，你竟敢讨价还价
Your world in the balance, and you bargain for one man.
改朝换代是常有的事
Regimes fall every day.
我都不在乎，我是俄国人
I tend not to weep over that. I'm Russian.
曾是
Or I was.
现在呢？
And what are you now?
很简单
It's really not that complicated.
我要还清血债
I got red in my ledger, I'd like to wipe it out.
行吗？
Can you?
能还清吗？
Can you wipe out that much red?
得雷科夫的女儿
Dreykov's daughter,
圣保罗…
São Paulo,
医院失火事件？
the hospital fire?
巴顿已对我和盘托出
Barton told me everything.
你背负不少血债
Your ledger is dripping. It's gushing red
单凭拯救个不比你好多少的人
and you think saving a man no more virtuous than yourself
就可以令自己良心好过？
will change anything?
未免太过自以为是
This is the basest sentimentality.
简直幼稚
This is a child at prayer.
太可怜
Pathetic!
你满口胡言，杀戮无数
You lie and kill
助纣为虐
in the service of liars and killers.
（发现病毒 非法入侵）
你以为可以置身事外
You pretend to be separate,to have your own code,something that makes up for the horrors.
但江山易改
But they are part of you.
本性难移
And they will never go away.
巴顿没杀死你之前，我不会杀他
I won't touch Barton, not until I make him kill you.
我要他用尽你所恐惧的方式
Slowly, intimately,
驾轻就熟地杀死你
in every way he knows you fear.
当他苏醒时，见到自己的所为
And then he'll wake just long enough to see his good work
就会尖叫，而我会趁机取他首级
and when he screams, I'll split his skull.
这就是我的目的，哭吧，贱人
This is my bargain, you mewling quim.
怪物
You're a monster.
噢，不
Oh, no.
你带来的那个才是怪物
You brought the monster.
利用班纳
So, Banner.
这就是你的计划
That's your play.
什么？
What?
洛基计划利用班纳
Loki means to unleash the Hulk.
令班纳留在实验室，我马上过来
Keep Banner in the lab. I'm on my way.
顺道也让托尔过来
Send Thor as well.
多谢
Thank you
你的合作
for your cooperation.
干嘛，史塔先生
What are you doing, Mr. Stark?
我同你有一样的疑惑
Uh, kind of been wondering the same thing about you.
你本该追踪立方的位置
You're supposed to be locating the Tesseract.
没错，已经锁定位置
We are. The model's locked
正在匹配标记
and we're sweeping for the signature now.
顺利的话
When we get a hit,
就可以锁定目标于半公里范围内
we'll have the location within half a mile.
接着就可以拿回立方，别着急
Yeah, then you get your Cube back. No muss, no fuss.
何为「第二阶段」？
What is "Phase 2"?
第二阶段是神盾局会利用立方制作武器
Phase 2 is S.H.I.E.L.D. uses the Cube to make weapons.
对不起，电脑不如我反应快
Sorry, computer was moving a little slow for me.
罗杰斯，我们收集了所有有关立方的信息
Rogers, we gathered everything related to the Tesseract.
这不代表我们要制作…
This does not mean that we're making...
得了
I'm sorry, Nick.
你还想狡辩
What were you lying?
原来如此
I was wrong, Director.
世界还是没有改变
The world hasn't changed a bit.
你知情？
Did you know about this?
博士，你想离开这里吗？
You want to think about removing yourself from this environment, Doctor?
我在加尔各答时，也很想离开
I was in Calcutta. I was pretty well removed.
洛基在利用你
Loki is manipulating you.
那你呢？
And you've been doing what, exactly?
你不是因我对你抛媚眼而来这里
You didn't come here because I bat my eyelashes at you.
那我也不会因为你觉得不安而离开
Yes, and I'm not leaving because suddenly you get a little twitchy.
我想知道为什么
I'd like to know why S.H.I.E.L.D.
神盾局要利用立方来制作大杀伤力武器
is using the Tesseract to build weapons of mass destruction.
因为他
Because of him.
我？
Me?
去年，有异星客来访地球
Last year, Earth had a visitor from another planet
异星客间的斗争摧毁了一个小镇
who had a grudge match that leveled a small town.
我们才知道原来天外有生命
We learned that not only are we not alone
而且相较之下，人类简直不堪一击
but we are hopelessly, hilariously, outgunned.
我的臣民只想和你们和平共处
My people want nothing but peace with your planet.
你不是唯一的天外生命体
But you're not the only people out there, are you?
难保没有其他生命体威胁地球
And you're not the only threat.
正所谓一山还有一山高
The world's filling up with people who can't be matched,
世事难以控制
that can't be controlled.
所以要控制立方？
Like you controlled the Cube?
正因为你开发立方
Your work with the Tesseract
才招致洛基等人到来
is what drew Loki to it, and his allies.
你已经向九大领域传达一个信息
It is a signal to all the realms
宣布地球已经准备好高规格战斗
that the Earth is ready for a higher form of war.
高规格战斗
A higher form?
你逼人在先
You forced our hand.
我们总要有对策
We had to come up with something.
用核武器镇压
A nuclear deterrent.
这总能避免大动干戈
Because that always calms everything right down.
我倒忘了你可是发战争财起家的
Remind me again how you made your fortune, Stark.
若他仍制作武器，他就会…
I'm sure if he still made weapons, Stark would be neck-deep...
干嘛矛头对向我了？
Hold on. How is this now about me?
你不是喜欢一切对向你吗？
I'm sorry, isn't everything?
还以为人类已经高度文明了
I thought humans were more evolved than this.
再怎么也不会跑到尊星球打仗啦
Excuse me, did we come to your planet and blow stuff up?
你们如此不信任你的战友
You treat your champions with such mistrust.
你们好天真啊
Are you boys really that naïve?
神盾局监视潜在危险
S.H.I.E.L.D. monitors potential threats.
美国队长也是潜在威胁?
Captain America's on threat watch?
我们都是
We all are.
你也在监视列表上？
Wait, you're on that list?
你在强忍怒气吗？
Are you above or below angry bees?
史塔，你试试再耍嘴皮…
Stark, so help me God, if you make one more wisecrack...
威胁我！我好怕啊
Threat! Verbal threat. I feel threatened.
- 放尊重点 - 尊重什么？
- Show some respect. - Respect what?
运输机66B，请回复确认代码
Transport Six-Six-Bravo, please relay confirm codes.
电脑中找到你的资料，但不是在航行日志中
I've got you on the computer, but not on the day log.
请告知货物
What is your haul? Over.
武器和弹药
Arms and ammunition. Over.
说到秩序，这里不也一团糟
You speak of control, yet you court chaos.
这就是他的管理手法
That's his M.O., isn't it?
我们还是一个团队吗？
I mean, what are we, a team?
我们只是制造混乱的化学怪物
No, we're a chemical mixture that makes chaos.
我们是定时炸弹
We're a time bomb.
你冷静下
You need to step away.
为何不让人发泄下？
Why shouldn't the guy let off a little steam?
明知故问，走开
You know damn well why. Back off!
你有本事让我走开吗
I'm starting to want you to make me.
躲在盔甲内装英雄
Yeah. Big man in a suit of armour.
没有盔甲，你还能是什么？
Take that off, what are you?
是天才，富翁，花花公子，慈善家
Genius, billionaire, playboy, philanthropist.
很多没有那些头衔的人，都比你厉害
I know guys with none of that worth ten of you.
我看过你的镜头
I've seen the footage.
你只会为自己而战
The only thing you really fight for is yourself.
你不会顾全大局
You're not the guy to make the sacrifice play,
你不会躺在铁丝网，让别人走过
to lay down on a wire and let the other guy crawl over you.
我会剪掉铁丝
I think I would just cut the wire.
就会耍急智
Always a way out.
你或许构不成威胁
You may not be a threat
但你别再假装是英雄
but you better stop pretending to be a hero.
像你这样的英雄？
A hero? Like you?
你只是个实验品
You're a laboratory experiment, Rogers.
你的超能力只是来自一瓶血清
Everything special about you came out of a bottle.
穿上盔甲，咱们打下
Put on the suit. Let's go a few rounds.
你们好小气
You people are so petty and tiny.
这就是一个团队
Yeah, this is a team.
罗曼诺夫特工，请你护送
Agent Romanoff, would you escort
班纳博士回去…
Dr. Banner back to his...
回哪去？你已经把我的房间占了
Where? You rented my room.
那只是以防…
The cell was just in case...
以防你想杀了我
In case you needed to kill me.
不过那是不可能的，我曾试过
But you can't. I know, I tried.
最低潮时期，我万念俱灰
I got low. I didn't see an end.
我饮弹自尽，可绿巨人却吐出来
So, I put a bullet in my mouth, and the other guy spit it out.
所以我死不成
So I moved on.
之后我致力帮助他人，本来相安无事
I focused on helping other people. I was good.
直到你拉我回到这个怪物聚会
Until you dragged me back into this freak show
把所有人置于危险之中
and put everyone here at risk.
想知道我的秘诀吗，罗曼诺夫探员？
You want to know my secret, Agent Romanoff?
想知道我怎么保持冷静？
You want to know how I stay calm?
班纳博士
Dr. Banner,
放下权杖
put down the sceptre.
（伽马射线 吻合度百分之九十五）
找到了
Got it.
对不起，孩子们
Sorry, kids,
你们见识不到我的拿手好戏了
you don't get to see my party trick after all.
找到立方？
You located the Tesseract?
我可以很快到达
I could get there fastest.
立方属于亚斯加特，人类无法驾驭它
The Tesseract belongs on Asgard. No human is a match for it.
- 你不能独自去 - 你要阻止我？
- You're not going alone. - You're gonna stop me?
穿上盔甲，比试下
Put on the suit, let's find out.
我才不怕和老年人打架
I'm not afraid to hit an old man.
穿上盔甲
Put on the suit.
（伽马射线定位）
噢，我的天啊
Oh, my God.
穿上盔甲
Put on the suit.
耶
Yeah.
各就各位
All hands to stations.
机身外部受袭
External detonation.
三号引擎停止运作
Number three engine is down.
我们受袭
We've been hit.
- 能否重运作？ - 三号引擎着火
- Can they get it running? - Fire in engine three!
具体如何
Talk to me.
涡轮似乎完好
Turbine looks mostly intact
但在空中无法修复机件
but it's impossible to get out there to make repairs while we're in the air.
再多个引擎坏掉，就会坠机
If we lose one more engine, we won't be.
要派人出去修复引擎
Somebody's got to get outside and patch that engine.
- 史塔，收到吗？ - 我马上去
- Stark, you copy that? - I'm on it.
古逊，关押区实施防御封锁
Coulson, initiate defensive lockdown in the detention section
然后去军火库
then get to the armoury.
罗曼诺夫？
Romanoff?
我们没事
We're okay.
会没事的
We're okay, right?
- 不要让他们修复引擎 - 遵命
- Keep that engine down! - Yes, sir.
去关押区，等待监视器关闭
Detention, wait for cameras to go dark.
- 收到 - 跟紧
- Got it. - Stay close.
走，到第四层
Let's go, Level 4.
三号引擎，在那里碰头
Engine three. I'll meet you there.
博士？
Doctor?
布斯？
Bruce?
冷静，否则正中洛基下怀
You got to fight it. This is just what Loki wants.
听着，会没事的
We're going to be okay. Listen to me.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
会没事的
We're going to be okay. All right?
我以性命担保，我会救你出去
I swear on my life, I will get you out of this.
你可以从此不问世事
You will walk away and never ever...
以你性命担保？
Your life?
布斯
Bruce.
水平翻转机身，朝南前进！
Bring the carrier about to a 1-8-0, heading south!
- 飞到海面 - 我们失去了导航
- Take us to the water! - We're flying blind.
导航系统在重新校准
Navigation's recalibrating after the engine failure.
还没日出吗？
Is the sun coming up?
- 对 - 对照太阳找方向
- Yes, sir. - Then put it on the left.
飞到海面
Get us over water.
再多个引擎失事，就会坠机
One more turbine goes down, and we drop.
- 谢谢
- Thanks.
史塔
Stark!
史塔，我来了
Stark, I'm here!
好
Good.
看下情况如何
Let's see what we've got.
我要让这个超导制冷系统
I got to get this superconducting coolant system
重运作
back online
接近回转轴前
before I can access the rotors,
我要清理残骸
work on dislodging the debris.
你到引擎控制箱
I need you to get to that engine control panel
告诉我哪个继电器超荷
and tell me which relays are in overload position.
控制箱是怎样的？
What does it look like in there?
一堆电路板的样子吗？
It seems to run on some form of electricity.
你说得没错
Well, you're not wrong.
我们不是你的敌人，班纳
We are not your enemies, Banner.
醒醒
- Try to think!
继电器正常了
Okay, the relays are intact.
接下来呢？
What's our next move?
即使我修复回转轴
Even if I clear the rotors,
这东西也要借外力才能动起来
this thing won't re-engage without a jump.
我要入内推动
I'm going to have to get in there and push.
如果转速加剧，会搅碎你
If that thing gets up to speed, you'll get shredded.
定子控制单元能翻转磁极
That stator control unit can reverse the polarity
会有足够时间脱离磁浮力
long enough to disengage maglev and that could...
听不懂
Speak English!
看到红色扳手吗？
You see that red lever?
可以降低转速，提供足够时间让我出去
It will slow the rotors down long enough for me to get out.
就位，等我信号
Stand by it. Wait for my word.
要清空下层机舱
We need full evac on the lower hangar bay.
手榴弹！
Grenade!
有入侵者
We've got a perimeter breach!
有人入侵神盾局
Hostiles are in S.H.I.E.L.D. gear.
各就各位
Call-outs at every junction.
绿巨人和托尔在第四层实验室
We have the Hulk and Thor on Research Level 4.
二三两层没信号
Levels 2 and 3 are dark.
长官，绿巨人会摧毁整艘船
Sir, the Hulk will tear this place apart!
转移他注意力
Get his attention.
护航舰6-0到Y形区迎战
Escort 6-0, proceed to Wishbone and engage hostile.
别靠得太近
Don't get too close.
收到
Copy.
发现目标
Target acquired.
锁定目标
Target engaged.
目标发飙了
Target angry, target angry!
他们不准备攻破这里，那究竟…
They're not getting through here, so what the hell...
（一号引擎出现故障）
一号引擎停止运行
Engine one is now in shut-down.
飞船坠落中
We are in an uncontrolled descent.
长官，一号引擎无法运作
Sir, we've lost all power in engine one.
巴顿摧毁了我们的系统
It's Barton.He took out our systems.
他正前往关押区
He's headed for the detention level.
有人听到吗？
Does anybody copy?
我是罗曼诺夫
This is Agent Romanoff.
收到
I copy.
史塔，我们要坠毁了
Stark, we're losing altitude.
我知道了
Yeah, I noticed.
不
No!
这招对你真是屡试不爽
Are you ever not going to fall for that?
人类认为我们是不死之身
The humans think us immortal.
要试下吗？
Should we test that?
请让开
Move away, please.
喜欢吗？
You like this?
自你派来毁灭者后，我们就开始研制
We started working on the prototype after you sent the Destroyer.
我不知道它能干什么
Even I don't know what it does.
想见识下吗？
- Do you want to find out?
不
No!
娜塔莎
Natasha?
你必败无疑
You're going to lose.
是吗
Am I?
你本性使然
It's in your nature.
你们的团队四分五裂
Your heroes are scattered.
你们空中要塞要堕落
Your floating fortress falls from the sky.
我有何弱点？
Where is my disadvantage?
你缺乏信念
You lack conviction.
我不觉得…
I don't think I'm...
原来有这样的威力
So, that's what it does.
队长，拉动扳手
Cap, hit the lever.
要等一下
I need a minute here!
快拉
Lever
马上
now!
哦 吼
Uh-oh.
救命
Help!
对不起，老大
Sorry, boss.
那家伙走了
The god rabbited.
保持清醒
Just stay awake.
看着我
Eyes on me.
我不行了
No, I'm clocking out here.
振作
Not an option.
没事的，老大
It's okay, boss.
这样下去不行的
This was never gonna work
除非他们能…
if they didn't have something
to...
古逊特工倒下了
Agent Coulson is down.
医疗部队正赶来
A medical team is on its way to your location.
他们已到了
They're here.
有人叫了
They called it.
在费尔·古逊外套里找到的
These were in Phil Coulson's jacket.
估计没来得及找你签名
I guess he never did get you to sign them.
我们在空中孤立无助
We're dead in the air up here.
通讯被断，立方又找不到
Our communications, the location of the Cube,
班纳和托尔不知所踪
Banner, Thor...
我也无能为力
I got nothing for you.
我失去了我的心腹
I lost my one good eye.
或许我罪有应得
Maybe I had that coming.
是
Yes,
我们打算利用立方制作武器
we were going to build an arsenal with the Tesseract.
但我没全把赌注压在这个上
I never put all my chips on that number, though
因为还有更值得一赌的东西
because I was playing something even riskier.
有个构思，史塔也知道的
There was an idea, Stark knows this,
称为复仇者计划
called the Avengers Initiative.
构思是聚集天赋异禀的人士
The idea was to bring together a group of remarkable people
看他们能否有更大作为
to see if they could become something more.
能否在需要时齐心协力
To see if they could work together when we needed them to,
应对本无胜算的战斗
to fight the battles that we never could.
古逊直到死前仍坚信此构思
Phil Coulson died still believing in that idea.
坚信你们会不负所托
In heroes.
好
Well,
这构思已过时
it's an old-fashioned notion.
你从天上掉下来
You fell out of the sky.
没砸伤到谁吧？
Did I hurt anybody?
没有
There's nobody around here to get hurt.
只是吓坏了鸽子而已
You did scare the hell out of some pigeons, though.
真好运
Lucky.
或者下落点选得好
Or just good aim.
你掉下来时还醒着
You were awake when you fell.
- 你看到了？ - 全程看到
- You saw? - The whole thing.
砸穿屋顶
Right through the ceiling.
又大又绿，一丝不挂
Big and green and buck-ass nude.
给
Here.
你恢复了正常尺寸，就能穿上这衣服
Didn't think those would fit you until you shrunk down to a regular-size feller.
多谢
Thank you.
你是外星人？
Are you an alien?
什么？
What?
来自外太空的外星人
From outer space, an alien.
不
No.
小子，你病得不轻
Well, then, son, you've got a condition.
克林，你会没事的
Clint. You're going to be all right.
你知道？
You know that?
你知道那感觉？
Is that what you know?
我无法呼吸
I've got no window.
我要赶他出去
I have to flush him out.
总得要花些时间恢复
You got to level out. It's going to take time.
你不明白
You don't understand.
你被他人控制过思想吗？
Have you ever had someone take your brain and play?
自我被赶走，用其他代替
Pull you out and stuff something else in?
明白心智被摧毁的感觉吗？
Do you know what it's like to be unmade?
你知道我有过
You know that I do.
我怎么苏醒的
Why am I back?
你怎么赶走他的？
How did you get him out?
重校你的思想
Cognitive recalibration.
我狠狠地打了你的脑袋
I hit you really hard on the head.
多谢
Thanks.
娜塔莎
Natasha...
我杀了多少特工
How many agents did I...
别说了
Don't.
别这样折磨自己
Don't do that to yourself, Clint.
拜洛基所赐
This is Loki.
拜魔鬼和魔法所赐
This is monsters and magic,
这种事情难以预料
and nothing we were ever trained for.
洛基逃掉了？
Loki, did he get away?
你应该不知道他去哪了
I don't suppose you know where.
我不可能知道
I didn't need to know.
我也没问
I didn't ask.
他很快会有所行动
He's going to make his play soon, though.
就在今天
Today.
我们要阻止他
We got to stop him.
我们？
Yeah? Who's "we"?
包括剩下的人吧
I don't know. Whoever's left.
好
Well,
如果我射中洛基的眼眶
if I put an arrow through Loki's eye socket,
我定会高枕无忧
I would sleep better, I suppose.
你终于没事了
Now you sound like you.
那你呢
But you don't.
你只是间谍，不是士兵
You're a spy, not a soldier.
你却要参战，为什么？
Now you want to wade into a war. Why?
洛基对你做了什么？
What did Loki do to you?
不关他的事，我只是…
He didn't. I just...
娜塔莎
Natasha.
我也被洗脑过
I've been compromised.
我背负了不少血债
I got red in my ledger.
我要赎罪
I would like to wipe it out.
他结婚了吗
Was he married?
没有
No.
有个拉大提琴的女友吧
There was a cellist, I think.
我很难过
I'm sorry.
他貌似人不错
He seemed like a good man.
他是个笨蛋
He was an idiot.
为什么，因为他的信念？
Why? For believing?
单独对抗洛基
For taking on Loki alone.
他只是忠于职守
He was doing his job.
不应该由他对付洛基
He was out of his league. He should have waited.
他应该…
He should have...
总有不由自主的时候
Sometimes there isn't a way out, Tony.
我明白
Right, I've heard that before.
你第一次看到士兵死亡？
Is this the first time you lost a soldier?
我们不是士兵
We are not soldiers.
我不是霍利的手下
I'm not marching to Fury's fife.
我也不是
Neither am I.
他和洛基一样手染鲜血
He's got the same blood on his hands that Loki does.
现在，我们要摒弃前嫌
But right now, we got to put that behind us
齐心协力解决事情
and get this done.
洛基需要能源
Loki needs a power source.
如果我们可以列出…
If we can put together a list...
他喜欢挑拨离间
He made it personal.
这不要紧
That's not the point.
这就是洛基的意图
That is the point. That's Loki's point.
他为什么会袭击我们的飞船？
He hit us all right where we live. Why?
分裂我们
To tear us apart.
对，逐个击破
Yeah, divide and conquer is great
只有除掉我们，他才会赢，对不？
but he knows he has to take us out to win, right?
这就是他的目的
That's what he wants.
他想击败我们，并被世人知道
He wants to beat us, he wants to be seen doing it.
他想要观众
He wants an audience.
对， 我知道他在斯图加特的所作所为
Right. I caught his act in Stuttgart.
对，那只是预告，现在才是首映
Yeah, that was just previews. This is opening night.
洛基是公主病患者
And Loki, he's a full-tilt diva, right?
他渴望鲜花，关注
He wants flowers, he wants parades.
他想要座铭刻其名的擎天大厦
He wants a monument built to the skies with his name plastered...
糟糕了
Son of a bitch.
（史塔大厦）
该走了
Time to go.
- 去哪？ - 路上会告诉你
- Go where? - I'll tell you on the way.
会开飞机吗？
Can you fly one of those jets?
我会
I can.
有制服吗？
You got a suit?
换上
Then suit up.
你们无权来此
Hey, you guys aren't authorised to be in here.
别多管闲事
Son, just don't.
长官
Sir.
希尔特工
Agent Hill.
这些卡片
Those cards,
可是在古逊的柜子里找到的
they were in Coulson's locker, not in his jacket.
不然他们就没动力干活
They needed the push.
6号停机坪有人擅自起飞
We have an unauthorised departure from Bay 6.
他们找到洛基了
They found him.
尽快恢复通讯
Get our communications back up, whatever you have to do.
- 我要掌握情况 - 遵命
- I want eyes on everything. - Yes, sir.
我已关闭弦反应炉堆
Sir, I've turned off the arc reactor
但立方已经自我运作
but the device is already self-sustaining.
关掉，绍韦博士
Shut it down, Dr. Selvig.
太迟了
It's too late!
停不下来了
She can't stop now.
它要向我们展示…
She wants to show us something!
一个全新的宇宙
A new universe.
Okay.
是纯能量防护罩
The barrier is pure energy.
无法击破
It's unbreachable.
明白
Yeah, I got that.
实行B计划
Plan B.
装甲MK7型号仍未准备好
Sir, the Mark 7 is not ready for deployment.
那就不要转轮了，没时间了
Then skip the spinning rims. We're on the clock.
你来求我大发慈悲？
Please tell me you're going to appeal to my humanity.
其实我是来吓你的
Actually, I'm planning to threaten you.
你最好穿上盔甲
You should have left your armour on for that.
Yeah.
没多大用处
It's seen a bit of mileage,
你可是拿着命运光杖
and you've got the glow stick of destiny.
喝一杯吗？
Would you like a drink?
拖延时间是没用的
Stalling me won't change anything.
不，是恐吓你
No, no. Threatening.
不喝？确定？
No drink? Are you sure?
那我自己喝
I'm having one.
智塔利军队将至，已成大局
The Chitauri are coming. Nothing will change that.
我还有什么好怕的？
What have I to fear?
复仇者联盟
The Avengers.
这是我们团队的名字
That's what we call ourselves. We're sort of like a team.
类似漫威动画「地球最强战队」
"Earth's mightiest heroes" -type thing.
见识过了
Yes, I've met them.
花了一些功夫才团结起来
It takes us a while to get any traction,
保证吓死你
I'll give you that one.
来点个人数吧
But let's do a head count, here.
你的半人神兄弟
Your brother, the demigod,
由传奇中苏醒过来的超级士兵
a super soldier, a living legend who kind of lives up to the legend.
怒火冲天的绿巨人
A man with breathtaking anger-management issues,
一对大师级刺客，可惜你…
a couple of master assassins, and you, big fella,
得罪了他们每一个
you've managed to piss off every single one of them.
这就是计划
That was the plan.
不咋样
Not a great plan.
等他们进来
When they come,
绝对会来
and they will,
冲着你而来
they'll come for you.
我有军队
I have an army.
我们有绿巨人
We have a Hulk.
我还以为那绿怪兽走了
I thought the beast had wandered off.
你没有搞清楚，这里没有王座
You're missing the point. There is no throne.
你不可能称王称霸
There is no version of this where you come out on top.
即使我们无法击败你的军队
Maybe your army comes and maybe it's too much for us,
那也要怪你
but it's all on you.
如果拯救不了世界
Because if we can't protect the Earth,
我们会找你复仇
you can be damn well sure we'll avenge it.
如果你和他们翻脸了
How will your friends have time for me
还会有时间对付我吗？
when they are so busy fighting you?
通常会成功的
This usually works.
发挥失常，不算稀奇
Well, performance issues, it's not uncommon.
五个男人就有一个不举
One out of five...
佐维斯，行了吧
Jarvis, anytime now.
你们将臣服于我
You will all fall before me.
启动
Deploy!
你还得罪了另一个人
And there's one other person you pissed off.
他叫费尔
His name was Phil.
不妙了
Right.
敌军来了
Army.
洛基！
Loki!
关闭立方，否则我就摧毁它
Turn off the Tesseract, or I'll destroy it.
你摧毁不了的
You can't.
大局已定
There is no stopping it.
唯有
There is only
开战
the war.
放马过来
So be it.
史塔，我们在你三点钟方向，朝东北来
Stark, we're on your three, headed northeast.
什么？你们路上还有闲情用膳？
What? Did you stop for drive-through?
快到帕克街，我会引敌人过来
Swing up Park. I'm going to lay them out for you.
长官，又多了一批
Sir, we have more incoming.
行，别让他们消停
Fine. Let's keep them occupied.
- 娜塔莎？ - 我看到他了
- Nat? - I see him.
我们得回到上面
We got to get back up there.
史塔，看到了吗？
Stark, are you seeing this?
看到了，难以置信
Seeing.Still working on believing.
班纳呢？来了吗？
Where's Banner? Has he shown up yet?
班纳？
Banner?
有进展就告诉我
Just keep me posted.
佐维斯，找出它们的弱点
Jarvis, find me a soft spot.
看这
Look at this!
看你周围
Look around you!
这场混乱会随着你的统治而告终吗？
You think this madness will end with your rule?
太迟了
It's too late.
为时已晚
It's too late to stop it.
只要我们齐心，就能做到
No. We can, together.
你又感情用事
Sentiment.
仍有一些市民困在这里
We've got civilians still trapped up here.
洛基
Loki.
这些人需要帮助
They're fish in a barrel down there.
这里交给我们，去吧
We got this. It's good. Go.
你们能牵制他们？
Do you think you can hold them off?
队长
Captain,
乐意之极
it would be my genuine pleasure.
令我想起在布达佩斯的情形
Just like Budapest all over again.
看来你我对布达佩斯的印象大不相同
You and I remember Budapest very differently.
国民兵要一小时后才到达
It's going to be an hour before they can scramble the National Guard.
国民兵？
National Guard?
军方了解这里的情况吗？
Does the army know what's happening here?
我们了解吗？
Do we?
派人进去这几栋楼
You need men in these buildings.
里面的人处境危险
There are people inside and they're going to be running right into the line of fire.
你们保护他们到地下室或者地铁
You take them to the basements or through the subway.
不要出现在街面上
You keep them off the streets.
封锁这里至第39街
I need a perimeter as far back as 39th.
为什么要听你指挥？
Why the hell should I take orders from you?
派人进去这几栋楼
I need men in those buildings.
带他们离开街面
Lead the people down and away from the streets.
封锁这里至第39街
We're going to set up a perimeter all the way down to 39th Street.
吸引它注意了
Well, we got its attention.
下一步呢？
What the hell was step two?
上面情况如何？
What's the story upstairs?
无法穿透立方周围的能量罩
The power surrounding the Cube is impenetrable.
托尔说得对，先干掉这些家伙
Thor's right. We got to deal with these guys.
- 怎么做？ - 大家一起做
- How do we do this? - As a team.
我还要找洛基算账呢
I have unfinished business with Loki.
轮着来，别插队啊
Yeah? Well, get in line.
省省吧
Save it.
洛基会集中火力于我们
Loki's going to keep this fight focused on us,
正好如此
and that's what we need.
没有他，这些怪物会乱阵脚
Without him, these things could run wild.
史塔在上面，他需要我们…
We got Stark up top. He's going to need us to...
挺混乱的
So, this all seems horrible.
我见过更混乱的
I've seen worse.
对不起
Sorry.
我们要将场面弄得更混乱些
No, we could use a little worse.
- 史塔，他来了 - 班纳吗？
- Stark, we got him. - Banner?
你猜对了
Just like you said.
叫他快变身，马上好戏开场
Then tell him to suit up. I'm bringing the party to you.
这不是好戏吧
I don't see how that's a party.
班纳博士
Dr. Banner.
是时候愤怒了
Now might be a really good time for you to get angry.
这就是我的秘诀，队长
That's my secret, Captain.
我总是在发怒
I'm always angry...
撑住
Hold on!
倾巢出动
Send the rest.
大家
Guys.
请发号施令，队长
Call it, Captain.
听好
All right, listen up.
关闭传送门前，要牵制住局势
Until we can close that portal, our priority is containment.
巴顿，你到屋顶
Barton, I want you on that roof.
盯住局势，有异常马上报告
Eyes on everything. Call out patterns and strays.
史塔，你负责封锁区
Stark, you got the perimeter.
有跑出三个街区的
Anything gets more than three blocks out,
你就把它抓回来或者消灭掉
you turn it back or you turn it to ash.
- 能带我一程吗？- 没问题
- Can you give me a lift? - Right.
抓紧，神射手
Better clench up, Legolas.
托尔，你负责阻塞传送门
Thor, you got to try and bottleneck that portal.
拖慢敌军的行速
Slow them down.
用雷电杀敌
You got the lightning. Light the bastards up.
你和我就留守地面
You and me, we stay here on the ground.
继续作战
We keep the fighting here.
至于浩克
And Hulk...
给我砸
Smash.
长官
Sir.
理事会在线
The Council is on.
史塔，有很多敌人尾随你
Stark, you got a lot of strays sniffing your tail.
我只是不想他们到街面上
I'm just trying to keep them off the streets.
可是存太多又不值钱
Well, they can't bank worth a damn.
找个急转弯
So find a tight corner.
收到
I will roger that.
好，伙计
Oh, boy.
好主意
Nice call.
还有别的招吗？
What else you got?
托尔在第六街与敌人作战
Thor is taking on a squadron down on Sixth.
竟敢不邀请我
And he didn't invite me.
队长，赶紧关上传送门
Captain, none of this is going to mean a damn thing
敌人太多了
if we don't close that portal.
用上巨炮也于事无补
Our biggest guns couldn't touch it.
或许不是枪炮的问题
Well, maybe it's not about guns.
想上去，你得有顺风车
If you want to get up there, you're going to need a ride.
找到顺风车了
I got a ride.
需要点助力
I could use a boost, though.
真要？
Are you sure about this?
会很好玩
Yeah. It's gonna be fun.
转弯
Okay, turn, turn.
慢点
Less! Less!
（中央火车站四十二大街站）
队长，42街过麦迪逊大道处的银行
Captain, the bank on 42nd past Madison.
有大批市民被困
They've cornered a lot of civilians in there.
我马上过来
I'm on it.
大家，快离开
Everyone! Clear out!
霍利局长
Director Fury,
理事会已作出决定
the Council has made a decision.
知道了
I recognise the Council has made a decision.
肯定是个白痴决定
But given that it's a stupid-ass decision,
所以我选择无视
I have elected to ignore it.
局长，你最靠近战场
Director, you're closer than any of our subs.
你爬上飞机…
You scramble that jet...
那可是曼哈顿岛，议员们
That is the island of Manhattan, Councilman.
除非我的队伍阻挡不了
Until I'm certain my team can't hold it,
否则我不会下令发动核武攻击
I will not order a nuclear strike
来对付市民
against a civilian population.
如果真的制止不了，那就完蛋了
If we don't hold them here, we lose everything.
发动核武攻击才是真的完蛋
If I send that bird out, we already have.
是你
Oh, you.
鹰眼
Hawkeye!
娜塔莎，你干什么？
Nat, what are you doing?
帮下忙？
A little help?
没问题
I got him.
够了
Enough!
你们只不过是低等生物
You are, all of you, beneath me!
我是神明，愚蠢的生物
I am a god, you dull creature.
我绝不妥协…
And I will not be bullied by...
弱神一个
Puny god.
权杖
The sceptre...
博士
Doctor.
洛基的权杖所拥有的力量
Loki's sceptre. The energy.
可以对付立方
The Tesseract can't fight,
因为彼此的力量是同类
but you can't protect against yourself.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你当时不知道自己在做什么
You didn't know what you were doing.
其实我是知道的
Actually, I think I did.
我设立了安全罩，以便切断能量源
I built in a safety to cut their power source.
洛基的权杖
Loki's sceptre.
应该可以关闭传送门
It may be able to close the portal.
它就近在眼前
And I'm looking right at it.
先生，我们的能量会在穿透护甲前用尽
Sir, we will lose power before we penetrate that shell.
佐维斯，听过约拿的故事吗？
Jarvis, you ever hear the tale of Jonah?
约拿可不是好榜样
I wouldn't consider him a role model.
霍利局长不再有话事权
Director Fury is no longer in command.
优先执行7A11
Override order 7-Alpha-1-1.
7A11,已确认，准备起飞
7-Alpha-1-1, confirmed. We're go for takeoff.
有飞机起飞
Sir, we have a bird in motion!
甲板上的人注意，有飞机擅自起飞
Anyone on the deck, we have a rogue bird.
拦截下来
We need to shut it down!
重复，行动未经许可
Repeat, takeoff is not authorised.
史塔，听到吗？
Stark, do you hear me?
有导弹直奔市中心
You have a missile headed straight for the city.
还有多久？
How long?
最多三分钟
Three minutes, max.
导弹会夷平市中心
The payload will wipe out Midtown.
佐维斯，将所有能量注入推进器
Jarvis, put everything we got into the thrusters.
完成了
I just did.
发射完毕
Package is sent.
两分三十秒后会爆炸
Detonation in 2 minutes, 30 seconds, mark.
有能力再战一回吗？
Are you ready for another bout?
怎么，你累了？
What, are you getting sleepy?
对准上端
Right at the crown!
我能关掉传送门
I can close it.
有人听到吗
Can anybody copy?
我能关掉传送门
I can shut the portal down.
- 赶快 - 等下
- Do it! - No, wait.
史塔，敌军不断攻入
Stark, these things are still coming.
有颗导弹正奔过来
I got a nuke coming in.
会在一分钟内爆炸
It's gonna blow in less than a minute.
我找到绝佳的爆炸场所
And I know just where to put it.
史塔，你有去无回
Stark, you know that's a one-way trip.
剩下的能量用来上升，佐维斯
Save the rest for the turn, J.
先生，要不要致电宝芝小姐？
Sir, shall I try Miss Potts?
也好
Might as well.
纽约市的街道变成了战场
The streets of New York City have become a battleground.
军方试图牵制敌方
The Army is here trying to contain the violence
不过实力悬殊
- but clearly, it is outmatched.
不得不说，鄙人多年新闻报道中
And I have to say, in all my years of reporting,
亦未曾见过如斯情形
I have never seen anything like this.
我方战斗小组的资料有限
We have limited information on the team
不过据知有亿万富翁史塔的钢铁侠
but we do know that billionaire Tony Stark's Iron Man...
（呼叫小辣椒失败）
(JARVIS POWERING DOWN)
快呀，史塔
Come on, Stark.
关掉
Close it.
臭小子
Son of a gun.
他没有减速
He's not slowing down.
还有呼吸吗？
Is he breathing?
怎么了？
What the hell?
干嘛？
What just happened?
不要告诉我，没人给我做人工呼吸
Please tell me nobody kissed me.
我们打赢了
We won.
太好了
All right, yay!
干得好
Hurray. Good job, guys.
明天不上班，休假一天吧
Let's just not come in tomorrow. Let's just take a day.
吃过土耳其烤肉吗?
Have you ever tried shawarma?
离这里两个街口有档土耳其烤肉
There's a shawarma joint about two blocks from here.
虽然不清楚，但是我想试试
I don't know what it is, but I want to try it.
事情还没结束
We're not finished yet.
那就稍后再吃烤肉
And then shawarma after.
如果你们不介意
If it's all the same to you,
我想喝杯酒
I'll have that drink now.
此次灾难事件已确认为外星人袭击事件
Despite the devastation of what has been confirmed as an extraterrestrial attack,
一班天赋异禀人士
the extraordinary heroics
组成的复仇者联盟团队
of the group known as the Avengers
不但慰藉民心
has been to many a cause not only for comfort,
更被津津乐道
but for celebration.
有这样的人士守护我们，太好了
It's just really great knowing they're out there.That someone is watching over us.
我爱你，雷神托尔
I love you, Thor!
然后这些家伙…
And then these guys were like...
然后天空变得…
And then the air goes...
接着绿巨人走过来…
And this green guy walks up and he goes...
不知道
I don't know.
我并不觉得安全
I don't exactly feel safer with those things out there.
政府似乎有所隐瞒
It just seems that there's a lot they're not telling us.
超级英雄在纽约？别闹了
Superheroes in New York? Give me a break.
这般所谓的英雄
These so-called "heroes"
要对这所城市遭受的破坏负责
have to be held responsible for the destruction done to this city.
这是他们造成的，他们去哪了？
This was their fight. Where are they now?
尽管大家对这些英雄疑问多多
Tough questions are being asked about the Avengers themselves.
他们从天而降
Their sudden appearance
又突然消失
and equally sudden disappearance...
这也归咎于他们吗？
What, this is all somehow their fault?
美国队长救了我
Captain America saved my life.
无论他在哪里，无论他们在哪
Wherever he is, and wherever any of them are,
我只想…
I would just...
我只想道声谢
I would want to say thank you.
复仇者们去哪了？
Where are the Avengers?
我目前没追查他们的行踪
I'm not currently tracking their whereabouts.
但他们应该休息下
I'd say they've earned a leave of absence.
至于宇宙立方？
And the Tesseract?
立方回去了属于它的地方
The Tesseract is where it belongs.
一个我们去不到的地方
Out of our reach.
你无权话事
That's not your call.
我可没做什么
I didn't make it.
我只是遵循神的旨意
I just didn't argue with the god that did.
可你让他带走
So, you let him take it
至于战犯洛基
and the war criminal, Loki,
他应该为所犯下的负责
who should be answering for his crime.
他会的
Oh, I think he will be.
你根本不知道你在做什么
I don't think you understand what you've started,
对复仇者们放任不管
letting the Avengers loose on this world.
他们很危险的
They're dangerous.
全世界都知道
They surely are, and the whole world knows it.
全宇宙都知道
Every world knows it.
这就是你的目的？
Was that the point of all this?
声明？
A statement?
保证？
A promise.
长官，下一步怎么做？
Sir, how does it work now?
他们各奔天涯了
They've gone their separate ways.
有些还跑得相当远
Some, pretty extremely far.
如果再发生类似事件
If we get into a situation like this again,
要怎么办
what happens then?
他们会回来的
They'll come back.
你肯定？
Are you really sure about that?
没错
I am.
何以见得？
Why?
因为我们需要他们回来
Because we'll need them to.
人类
Humans.
并非我们想象中那么弱小
They are not the cowering wretches we were promised.
他们意志坚定
They stand.
桀骜不驯，因而难以奴役
They are unruly, and therefore cannot be ruled.
挑衅人类
To challenge them
等同自寻死路
is to court death.
谢谢观赏TLF字幕
双语校准修正：diksonhe
TLF中文字幕站欢迎你
http://sub.eastgame.org/